A Guide to the Papers of Rita Mae Brown 1929-2001
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Correspondence
  - Individual Correspondent Folders
    - Correspondence--Sophie B. Hawkins 1995 (Box 159)
    - Correspondence--Robert Hazel 1980-1988 (Box 159)
    - Correspondence--Karl Hess (1923-1994) [1979?]-1994 (Box 159)
    - Correspondence--Invitations 1979-2001, n.d., 4 folders (Box 159)
    - Correspondence--Rod and Bob Jackson-Paris 1993-1994 (Box 160)
    - Correspondence--Erica Jong 1994-1998, n.d. (Box 160)
    - Correspondence--Margarete Langsfield 1994-1998, n.d. (Box 160)
    - Correspondence--Norman Lear 1982-1988 (Box 160)
    - Correspondence--Alice Marble 1986-1989, n.d. (Box 160)
    - Correspondence--Miscellaneous Notes 1986-1995, n.d. (Box 160)
    - Correspondence--Miscellaneous Publishers 1978-2000, n.d. (Box 160)
    - Correspondence--Joseph B. Mitchell, 1915-1993 1986-1992, 3 folders (Box 160)
    - Correspondence--Rick Mitz 1984-1989 (Box 160)
    - Correspondence--Martina Navratilova 1980-1981, 1990-1996, n.d., 2 folders (Box 161)
    - Correspondence--Judy Nelson 1986-1996 (Box 161)
    - Correspondence--Nelle Nugent 1983-1989 (Box 161)
    - Correspondence--Paul and Peter Fritz Literary Agency 1994-2001 (Box 161)
    - Correspondence--Jeffery Pfeiffer 1965-1966, n.d. (Box 151)
      including one letter re his death and funeral from his parents, September 21, [1985]
    - Correspondence--Political Figures 1977, 1984-2000, n.d. (Box 161)
      including: Governor George Allen, Senator Birch Bayh, Senator Bill Bradley, Senator Edward W. Brooke, Barbara Bush, President Bill Clinton and Hillary Rodham Clinton, Vice-President Al Gore and Tipper Gore, Representative Jon Hinson, Rep. Carolyn Maloney, Rep. L.F. Payne, Ed Robb, Lynda Johnson Robb, Howard Russell, Secretary Donna E. Shalala, and Rep. Gerry E. Studds
    - Correspondence--Red Fox Fine Art 1983-1989 (Box 161)
    - Correspondence--Stu Robinson (1963-2000), Paradigm Talent and Literary Agency 1982-1993, 3 folders (Box 161)
    - Correspondence--Stu Robinson (1936-2000), Paradigm Talent and Literary Agency 1994-2000, n.d., 3 folders (Box 162)
    - Correspondence--David Rosenthal 1985-1991 (Box 162)
    - Correspondence--Rowohlt 1990-2000, n.d., 2 folders (Box 162)
    - Correspondence--Vito Russo 1985-1989 (Box 162)
    - Correspondence--Diane Salvatore 1984-2000 (Box 162)
    - Correspondence--Sandollar Productions 1985 (Box 162)
    - Correspondence--Maggie Siner 1989-1991 (Box 162)
    - Correspondence--Michele Slung 1989-1991 (Box 162)
    - Correspondence--Liz Smith 1980-1985 (Box 162)
    - Correspondence--Liz Smith 1986-2000, n.d., 4 folders (Box 163)
    - Correspondence--Elaine C. Spaulding 1978-1985 (Box 163)
    - Correspondence--Muffin Spencer-Devlin 1983-1990, n.d. (Box 163)
    - Correspondence--Gloria Steinem 1974-1997, n.d. (Box 163)
    - Correspondence--Mel Tolkin 1985-1989 (Box 163)
    - Correspondence--Tamara Trautner, Rowohlt 1992-1998, n.d., 2 folders (Box 163)
    - Correspondence--Ingrid Weber 1984-1993, 2 folders (Box 1963)
    - Correspondence--The Wendy Weil Agency 1974, 1979-2000, n.d., 7 folders (Box 164)
    - Correspondence--Lawrence Douglas Wilder 1989-1994 (Box 164)
    - Correspondence--Diana Williamson 1977-1989, n.d. (Box 164)
    - Correspondence--Allee Willis 1995 (Box 164)
- Calendar Diaries, Journals, Memorabilia, and Photographs
  - Appointment Calendar 1982 (Box 165)
  - Calendar Diaries--Large Format 1985-1987, 4 volumes (Box 165)
  - Calendar Diaries--Large Fomat 1992-1993, 1999, 3 volumes (Box 166)
  - Calendar Diaries--Small Format 1978, 1980-1988, 10 volumes (Box 167)
  - Calendar Diaries--Small Format 1989-1998, 10 volumes (Box 168)
  - Calendar Diaries--Pocket Size 1993-1994, 2 volumes (Box 168)
  - Calendars--Nine to Five Weekly 1989-1990, 1993-1996, 5 volumes (Box 169)
  - Calendar Pages--Miscellaneous 1999 (Box 169)
  - Journal kept by Julia Brown 1946 (Box 169)
    re Rita Mae Brown
  - Journals kept by Rita Mae Brown 1975-1983 Mar 28, 6 volumes (Box 169)
  - Memoranda Book n.d. (Box 169)
  - Memorabilia--Loose items 1954-1963, n.d. (Box 170)
    including, Souvenir Clothing Patches from New Zealand, San Francisco, Cazenovia, New York, Australia, and the New York Central System; Cat Collars; Pack of Playing Cards; Bumper Stickers; Political Pin for Barbara Mikulski; Christmas Greeting Novelties; Ink Stamper, "Despoit Only American Artists"; Nazi Belt Buckle; Princeton University Crest on Metal Disk; Key from Kansas City, Missouri; Souvenir, with Painting of the Thomas Wolfe Angel, Oakdale Cemetery, Hendersonville, North Carolina; Silver Bracelet; Souvenir Photograph Packets for Natural Bridge of Virginia and Richmond; High School Graduation Tassel; Tennis Pins; 4-H Beef and Livestock Ribbons; Track and Field Ribbons; and a Camp Hiawatha Horse Show Ribbon
  - Memorabilia--Computer Print-Out Birthday Greeting for Rita Mae Brown; Drawing of a Dog; Florida Girls State Pennant Flag; Camp Hiawatha Metal Sign; and a Tennis Letter 1961, 1982, n.d. (Box 171)
  - Memorabilia--Avantcards n.d. (Box 171)
    including one featuring Rubyfruit Jungle, for photographs upon which it is based--see Photographs--Publicity, n.d.
  - Memorabilia--Business Cards, Bookmarks, and Post Cards 1957, 1978, n.d. (Box 171)
  - Memorabilia--Caricature of Rita Mae Brown n.d. (Box 171)
  - Memorabilia--Two Large "Packets," one from someone at Rowohlt and one unidentified but with the words, "Expect the Unexpected" n.d. (Box 171)
  - Photographs--Rita Mae Brown ca. 1945-1990, n.d., 2 folders (Box 171)
  - Photographs--Rita Mae Brown--Publicity ca. 1982-1999, n.d., 2 folders (Box 171)
  - Photography--Miscellaneous 1975 and n.d. (Box 172)
  - Photographs--Negatives ca. 1978-1986, 1995, n.d. (Box 172)
  - Photographs--Slides pertaining to Women 1969, 2 folders (Box 172)
  - Photographs--Slides of Rita Mae Brown 1975-1985, 3 folders (Box 172)
  - Photographs--Snapshots--Rita Mae Brown--Childhood ca. 1958-1967, n.d. (Box 173)
  - Photographs--Snapshots--"Flordon," Albemarle County, Virginia [1981 Apr] (Box 173)
  - Photographs--Snapshots--Chiefly Cats, Dogs, and Horses ca. 1957-1987, n.d., 2 folders (Box 173)
  - Photographs--Snapshots--Family ca. 1929-1979, n.d., 3 folders (Box 173)
  - Photographs--Snapshots--Family n.d. (Box 174)
  - Photographs--Snapshots--Farm, Animals, and Hunts 1990, 2000 (Box 174)
  - Photographs--Snapshots--Friends ca. 1973-1984, n.d. (Box 174)
  - Photographs--Snapshots--Miscellaneous ca. 1981-1998, n.d., 2 folders (Box 174)
  - Photographs--Snapshots--Oak Ridge/De La Brooke Joint Meeting and Hunt 1998 (Box 174)
  - Photographs--Snapshots--Polo and Miscellaneous n.d. (Box 174)
  - Photographs--Unidentified [ca. 1965?] (Box 174)
  - Photograph Album [of Rita Mae Brown's] Farm [ca. 2000] (Box 175)
  - Telephone Memo Record 1989 Jul-1991 Oct, 7 volumes (Box 175)
  - Scrapbook for the Rita Mae Brown Gala 1984 Nov 16 (Box 175)
- Legal and Subject Files
  - Academy of Television Arts and Sciences 1982-1994, 2 folders (Box 176)
  - Addresses and Directions 1994-1995, n.d. (Box 176)
  - American Artists, Inc./Speakeasy, Inc. Incorporation Papers 1981-1990 (Box 176)
  - American Film Institute 1986-1994, n.d., 2 folders (Box 176)
  - Animals 1982-1995, n.d. (Box 176)
  - Artwork 1974-1976, n.d. (Box 176)
  - The Author's Guild, Inc. 1979-1992 (Box 176)
  - Bank Record Books from the Citizen's National Bank, Alexandria, Virginia, in account with Charles King and Son Company, Inc. ca. 1923-1929 (Box 177)
  - Josef Beery 1988-1992 (Box 177)
    re Graphic Design
  - Blue Ridge Polo Club 1988-1998, n.d. (Box 177)
  - Bright Books 1989-1991, n.d. (Box 177)
  - Calendar Sheets 1999, n.d. (Box 177)
  - Cat Items for Sale 1995-1996, n.d. (Box 177)
  - Christmas Address and Gift List 1986-1993, 1999, 3 folders (Box 177)
  - Contracts and Agreements 1978-1982, 1988-1999, 2 folders (Box 177)
  - Contracts and Agreements--Bantam 1993-1994 (Box 177)
  - The Crossing Press 1984-1994 (Box 178)
  - Curriculum Vitae and Biographical Entries 1979-2000, n.d., 3 folders (Box 178)
  - Farmington Equine Consultants, Inc., a company which provides equine services to film crews shooting in the Middle-Atlantic States 1989-1991 (Box 178)
  - Farmington Hunt Club and Related 1979-2000, n.d., 2 folders (Box 178)
  - Feminist Repertory and Experimental Ensemble (F.R.E.E.) n.d. (Box 178)
  - Florentine Films 1986 (Box 178)
  - Foxhunting--Miscellaneous 1996-2001, n.d. (Box 178)
  - Frost and Reed Fine Art Dealers 1990-2000 (Box 178)
  - The Furies Reunion and The Washington Blade Articles 1995-1996 (Box 179)
  - Goshen Hounds Foxhunting 1997 (Box 179)
  - High School for the Creative Arts--Research 1987 (Box 179)
  - Humor 1991-1994, n.d. (Box 179)
  - Institute for Policy Study 1972, 1985-86, 1993-94 (Box 179)
  - Legal--Lucius H. Bracey, Jr. of McGuire, Woods, and Battle 1981-1987, 1992-2000, 4 folders (Box 179)
  - Legal--Diana Press 1980 (Box 179)
  - Legal--Josie Martin--Correspondence and Record of Charges 1984-1986, 3 folders (Box 179)
  - Legal--Miscellaneous 1981-1991, 1998-1999 (Box 180)
  - Legal--Martina Navratilova 1980-1981 (Box 180)
    including contracts re "Flordon," Albemarle County, Virginia
  - Legal--Judy Nelson 1992, 1994-1995, 4 folders (Box 180)
  - Legal--Judy Nelson--Figures for Settlement ca. 1994 (Box 180)
  - Legal--Julia Penelope v. Rita Mae Brown, American Artists, and Bantam 1989-1990 (Box 180)
  - Legal--Julia Penelope v. Rita Mae Brown, American Artists, and Bantam 1991 and 1993, 4 folders (Box 181)
  - Legal--Property--"Beaulieu," Albemarle County, Virginia 1979-1984, 2 folders (Box 181)
  - Legal--Property--Los Angeles House 1978-1979 (Box 181)
  - Legal--Property--Nelson County, Virginia 1987-1998, 2 folders (Box 181)
  - Legal--Property--Nelson County, Virginia--House Design and Construction 1988-1991 (Box 181)
  - Legal--Property--Nelson County, Virginia--Loan 1987-1991 (Box 182)
  - Legal--Property--1900 Stillhouse Road, Ivy Farms, Virginia 1984-1988 (Box 182)
  - Legal--Rubyfruit Jungle 1979-1990 (Box 182)
  - Legal--Virginia Employment Commission 1995 (Box 182)
  - Magnus Films 1990 (Box 182)
    re Bingo
  - Martin Weiss Accounting Firm 1981-1982 (Box 182)
  - Miscellaneous, including Memorial Card for Ralph Brown ca. 1961-1993 (Box 182)
  - Montague, Miller, and Co. 1990 (Box 182)
  - Montpelier 1992-1994 (Box 182)
  - Ms. Foundation for Women 1984-1995, 2 folders (Box 182)
  - Navratilova/Evert Book Project 1987-1988 (Box 182)
  - Novel Notes--Miscellaneous n.d. (Box 182)
  - Oak Ridge Hunt Club 1993-2000, n.d., 7 folders (Box 183)
  - Oak Ridge Spring Fling Horse Show 1994 (Box 183)
  - Old Blue Equestrian Center 1994-1995 (Box 184)
  - Old Blue Equestrian Center--Infomation Request Form ca. 1994 (Box 184)
  - Passports 1968, 1976 (Box 184)
  - Personal Financial Statement ca. 1986-1987 (Box 184)
  - Piedmont Women's Polo Club 1990-1993, 2 folders (Box 184)
  - Printed Material--Miscellaneous 1993-1999, n.d. (Box 184)
  - Promotional Material 1989-2001, n.d., 2 folders (Box 184)
  - Reading List n.d. (Box 184)
  - Real Estate Research ca. 1990-1991 (Box 184)
  - Real Estate Research 1992-1997, n.d. (Box 185)
  - Research Material 1991-1992, n.d., 2 folders (Box 185)
  - Research Material--Railroads 1980, n.d. (Box 185)
  - Royalties--Bantam 1992-1994 (Box 185)
  - Royalties--Harper Collins 1992-1994 (Box 185)
  - Royalties--Wendy Weil Agency, Inc.--Author's Account Statements 1999-2000 (Box 185)
  - School and Childhood Papers--"Baby Book" of Rita Mae Brown, Easter Cards to Family, and Vacation Church School Certificate 1944-1955 (Box 185)
  - School and Childhood Papers--College Class Notes 1965-1966 (Box 185)
  - School and Childhood Papers--College Class Notes--Ancient Comedy 1967 (Box 186)
  - School and Childhood Papers--College Class Notes--Ancient Greece and Rome 1966 and n.d. (Box 186)
  - School and Childhood Papers--College Class Notes--History 1965 (Box 186)
  - School and Childhood--College Class Notes--Literature 1965-1966 (Box 186)
  - School and Childhood Papers--Diploma--Fort Lauderdale High School 1962 (Box 186)
  - School and Childhood Papers--Diploma--Junior College of Broward County 1965 (Box 186)
  - School and Childhood Papers--Dog Pedigree and "Last Will and Testament Class of 1961" 1958 and 1961 (Box 186)
  - School and Childhood Papers--Fort Lauderdale High School Reunions 1982 and 1992 (Box 186)
  - School and Childhood Papers--High School Class Notes 1961-1962, n.d. (Box 187)
  - School and Childhood Papers--High School Honors and College Honors 1959-1962 (Box 187)
  - School and Childhood Papers--Report Card and PSAT Scores 1949-1958, 1961 (Box 187)
  - Shiloh Farms 1997 (Box 187)
  - Sneaky Pie Brown--"Biography" and Proposals 1985-1991 (Box 187)
  - Sobek Expeditions 1990, n.d. (Box 187)
  - Sparrowhawk Publications 1994 (Box 187)
  - Stationary Samples 1994 (Box 187)
  - Story Structure Class--Robert McKee 1992 (Box 187)
  - Story Structure Class--John Truby 1985 (Box 187)
  - Tea Time Farm 1993-1998, n.d., 2 folders (Box 187)
  - Tennessee Arts Commission 1987-1991, n.d. (Box 187)
  - Trevi Publishers, Stockholm, Sweden 1989-1990 (Box 187)
  - Undercover Books 2000, n.d. (Box 187)
  - United States Polo Association 1999 (Box 188)
  - University of Virginia 1985-1993 (Box 188)
  - Virginia Festival of American Film 1989-1994 (Box 188)
  - Virginia Film Office 1989-1994, n.d. (Box 188)
  - Weather Observations 1997, n.d. (Box 188)
  - Web Site for Rita Mae Brown 1997-1999 (Box 188)
  - Writers Guild of America ca. 1984-1999, 2 folders (Box 188)